LYDIA TSANG

Data Analyst & Business Professional

Contact Details

****939-488-2141

™wmltsang@gmail.com

inlinkedin.com/in/lydiatsang

https://github.com/wmltsang

https://public.tableau.com/profile/wai.mai.lydia.tsang#!/

ABOUT ME

I am a curious and cheerful data analyst specializing in the field of business. I love problem-solving, and I enjoy understanding and visualizing data to better provide business insights and answers. I also have exceptional administration and customer service skills, which aid in listening and understanding problems that would benefit me as a Data Analyst.

EDUCATION

Nashville Software School | Jan 2021

Data Analytics Certification

Texas Wesleyan University | May 2019

Master of Business Administration, Health Care (GPA: 4.00) Honors: Beta Gamma Sigma

The Hong Kong Polytechnic University | Oct 2013

Bachelor of Science in Hotel Management

DATA EXPERIENCE

Nashville Software School | Jan 2021

Data Analyst

Six months of project experience using real-world data utilizing data exploratory and explanatory analysis applying business intelligence tools and programming languages to drive business resolution in excellency; Strong business background to understand the data and apply fundamental statistical knowledge for logical reasoning in problem-solving; Familiar with the agile process for group projects and used GitHub and Kanban board for effective collaboration

Lahman Baseball (PostgreSQL)

https://github.com/wmltsang/lahaman-baseball-sql

Analyzed all the colleges in the State of Tennessee and used several metrics to find out which college had the most success in the major leagues

• Upon conducting an External Analysis to define success, used SQL to pull data in and applied necessary filters to stage data for Visual Graphs to represent findings for users

Covid-19 Analysis (Tableau)

https://public.tableau.com/profile/wai.mai.lydia.tsang#!/

Provided a summary and breakdown of countries' Covid-19 cases and conducted a statistical trend analysis with new deaths and new cases using linear regression methods

• Used a world map to show the highest cases area, narrowed down by WHO regions with tree maps, ranked countries with top cases and deaths, provided time-series graphs to present new cases and death trends

UN Data Analysis (Python)

https://github.com/wmltsang/united-nation-python

Conducted a correlation analysis of GDP per capita and internet usage among countries

 After merging data sets and applying cleaning scripts, created graphs that captured various trends among different countries as it related to Internet usage and GDP per capita

DATA CAPSTONE

How to promote community health and pursue a healthier lifestyle in Tennessee? (Excel, Python, Tableau) https://github.com/wmltsang/nss_capstone

Examined the relationship between lifestyle choices and obesity in Tennessee

• Used five datasets with one million+ rows from the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) to look at obesity problems at national, state and city levels

- Asked Data Questions on assessing health issues, prioritizing needs and actions needed
- Applied appropriate filters, utilized different perspectives and visuals to analyze data
- Cleaned data and constructed a folium map using Python to map the matched locations of obesity area with no activity
- Created a storyline using Tableau for presentation to students, professors, and potential employers

WORK EXPERIENCE

Department of Human Service | Feb 2017- Present

Administrative Assistant II

Administers numerous services by connecting Tennesseans to employment, education, and support services

- Excel at multi-tasking, while meeting tight deadlines for executives and teams delivering effective business outcomes managing more than 4000 active facilities
- Active initiator of making administrative and procedural decisions that can address potential issues for a monthly average of 2000 checks
- Pull data from SQL, and load to Excel, which is then used with Tableau to graphically represent key performance indicators and data visualizations needed on the Commissioner's Dashboard Report.
- Improve the reporting process in incident reporting and background checks coordinating interdepartmental efforts to transform process electronically, enhancing process productivity across 95 counties in Tennessee
- Maintain data system and organize records (improve productivity, reduce costs and save money with 28-cubic feet filings)
- Process invoices and troubleshoot record mismatch by managing state funding over 3 million that are essential for fiscal cost management and accuracy of financial outflow for all 12 departmental divisions
- Provide exceptional coordination and communication for all 12 divisions and external stakeholders that help fostering positive work relationships and ensure unit goals are on track

Gaylord Opryland Resort & Convention Center | Sep 2015-Jan 2017

Team Lead - Guest Service Agent and Trainer

One of the largest hotels in the world providing first-class customer service owned by Marriott International

- Active listener providing top-notch client service and daily problem solver handling customer complaints that effectively and economically solved customers' problems of daily average 1000 check-ins
- Executed 80,000 sales and financial daily transactions that contributed to maximizing revenues and resulted in higher guest satisfaction level
- Successfully provided training, coaching, and support to onboard and assign workflows for over 60 junior employees, which increased employee's engagement and performance productivity.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- •Data Analytics: Python, SQL, Tableau, Power BI
- Microsoft: Advanced Excel (Power Pivot, Vlookup), Word, PowerPoint, and Outlook
- Others: Remote Work/ Communication, Documentation, GitHub, GitBash

LANGUAGES

- English (Proficient)
- Cantonese (Native)
- Mandarin (Proficient)
- German (Intermediate)
- Korean (Basic)
- Spanish (Basic)

CERTIFICATIONS

SQL Fundamentals Track

Data Camp, Credential ID:129290

OTHER EXPERIENCE

Army and Air Force Exchange Service | Customer Service Representative | Fort Campbell, May – Sep 2015

Best Western Grand Hotel | Customer Service Receptionist | Hong Kong, Nov 2014 – Jan 2015

The Hotel Adlon Kempinski | Internship Berlin, International Trade Fair | Customer Service/Translator Düsseldorf | **Germany**, Aug 2013 – Aug 2014 Hotel & Exhibitions Customer Service Part-timer | **Hong Kong**, 2011-2012

Management Internship | Shanghai China, Jul - Dec 2010